We will be discussing about event if you are so I want to show you how to use
event via totally troubleshooting Windows server. The Windows event you are
shows a lot of applications and system messages including errors, information
message and warnings. So this is actually useful tool for troubleshooting all
kinds of different Windows problem. To start the event via what you need to do is
to go to your start menu and type event viewer or we can go to tools and from
tools we can totally start our event if you are and when you open the event via
here you can see it's the event if you are and we have our custom view Windows
log application and service log. We are totally interested in the Windows
log. On other Windows log you can see we have for example if I go to security
on a security it's good or I totally tell me when someone log on to the device
and when the person logs off which application I totally use this device to
log or you can see we have some log on and log off. For example you can see this
is an account was logged off and for example if I click the log on you see an
account was successfully logged on. So in here if I for example we can actually
see more details information on here it says all these sources and as a computer
name information answer does the event ID. So it is very very important for
example if you create a group policy so around the log on information of every
user to be set on this device definitely it's going to actually edit and save
the log on a log off of every single user that says the Windows server and here
we have applications. A lot of applications you can see we have different
applications which actually be recorded when applications started and if there
are any issues with the application it will also be listed here. Here you can
see we have for example we have the Azure Active Directory sync which is also
seen in server and kadana on the spreaded error. So here you go you're going to
see some very details information about some for example MS installer and some
other we have the VMware tools. So these are apps which are running on my
device it's going to display on that application. So here if I go to the set
of yeah you can see we have a 17 so it's going to be seen that for example
it says a little bit of the Microsoft Windows Group policy server means to update
of packet group. So here you just will have 17 which is going to be giving us
details information as it reboots a reboot it's necessary before packet in. So
these are all about updates and which I'm 10 years old but I totally mean you
can see that the KB updates so every update installed on this device we
will be ready to start here. And here if I go to the system which of course on
that system we're going to give us details information. If for example we try to
install an application or we try to install a software and it failed it's
going to actually record it here and give us detailed information of what
happened. For example you can see I'm seeing a lot of error missing TAC the
Microsoft Azure at this sync server service failed to start. So here it's
going to tell us all the different application that fails or which one
successfully started. So if I scroll down for example you can see we have a lot
of errors we see and all these are actually related because we have some
other information let me go back into my errors. All these you can see this just
the Azure ID sync that actually failed to start. And here you can see we have a
four event. This the four event is when you are trying to configure every event
to be forwarded to this device. After this window server the logs will be
forwarded to this server. For example you want other server so for the lock to
this device. And also we also have applications and service log. Let me go
to Microsoft on our Microsoft let me go to Windows. So when I click Windows
now you can see we have details information about different like the DNS
DSP this management even for example you will try to enroll Microsoft a
device to Microsoft Intune. You got to the troubleshoot if that device was able
to join Microsoft Intune unknowns by going to this location and here you're
going to see for example enterprise management we give you a detailed
information of when the device tries to register within tune and when it fails.
So here you can see details info that's got all the guide those. For example
let me just take let me just go up for example and let's let's let this if I
select this here you can see we have two info here you can see we have the
Microsoft Windows disk and the Microsoft Windows storage disk operation that's
much we don't have any information here but if I go to let me see if I can
have my DSP so here you can see we have some information here for example
the domain chain notification is received from DNS. So with this with events
viewer you can get some detailed information about what went wrong with
software installation which are device if you're device shot down unexpectedly
you can't only use the event you are totally troubleshoot and also the event
your ID we give us a number that can help us go to Google and set for the
specific result of that event ID if for example you are having issues of
specific software of your device reports I are receiving an error a blue screen
you can use that error code if I or the event ID code to go to Google I'm
trying to set if what I people have had similar issues in the past